Ben Cheah

+65 9127 3780 benjchb@gmail.com bencheah.com

1 Lorong 30 Geylang Singapore 398242 I'm a product designer who is fluent in both design and code. As the lead UX designer in a product team, I led and advocated for best practices in design research, usability testing, prototyping and accessibility.

Experience

- UX Designer, GovTech Singapore Jan 2018–Jan 2021
 As a UX lead of My Legacy, I led multiple features, including a major redesign of the website's information architecture. Outside of my project work, I also facilitated design studios for the UX team and managed two direct reports.
- Independent iOS Developer Jun 2016–Jul 2017
 Independently designed and developed an iPhone app for travellers to save places to their personal map. I integrated a reactive programming framework to streamline the software architecture and reduce complexity.
- UX Designer, RYDE Technologies Nov 2015–Apr 2016
 As the sole UX designer, I brought the team on board design thinking and guided product discussion to focus on the user perspective. In addition to user research and product design, I also developed tools and visualisations to improve data analytics.
- Web Developer, National University of Singapore Oct 2013–Apr 2015
 Design and development of a web-based course platform for the Special
 Science department. Lecturers can post content and quizzes for their
 students to complete.
- Data Visualisation Artist, Deloitte Analytics Jul 2012–Mar 2013
 I designed and developed interactive web apps and data visualisations which were used to demonstrate and sell complex data analytics concepts and cutting edge services to clients.

Education

- Nanyang Technological University, Singapore Bachelor of Fine Arts, 2008–2012
- Singapore Polytechnic Diploma in Multimedia Technology, 2003–2006

Skills

UX and UI design, design research, frontend web development.